No doubt about it. This is it!
I found the holy sword!
Salamander!
She dodged?!
Didn't she say we couldn't
so much as lay a finger on her?
Yup. Looks like our odds aren't
as hopeless as she thinks.
You'll pay for this...
What a performance.
How dare you...
How dare you break my horn?!
Whoa there, not so fast.
Come any closer, and I'll smash it.
Get your foot off that, human scum!
I know demons' horns are their pride,
to the point that the hornless
are considered subdemon.
Boy, the governor found an
elaborate way to hide this baby.
Is that the holy sword?
It's impeccably weighted and balanced.
It fits perfectly in my hand.
You bastard! Surrender the sword!
Yeah, I'm not handing this over
just because you said so.
I haven't even tested it out yet.
You filth...
I have a suggestion.
Why don't we call a temporary truce?
What?
What are you proposing?
We have sick and injured over here.
I don't want to press this fight.
Three days from now,
we'll meet again for a duel.
A duel, you say?
Yeah.
We'll return here to fight, and if you win,
we'll give you the sword and your horn.
Hey, that's not up to—
If we win, you'll tell us about the demons,
including who else of your kind
has infiltrated human society.
You'll give us all
the demon intelligence you have.
Don't worry. I'll face you solo.
Surely you wouldn't refuse a fair duel
against a human you see as inferior.
So be it.
Return here in three days' time!
Hey, I'm ba—
Sorry for making you worry.
Gazus, I'm so glad!
Hey!
So they really are lovers.
If anything happened to you, I...
Ya goober! Stop hugging me!
Go on! Get offa me!
Sorry to interrupt, Gazus and Miranda,
but I have some questions.
The governor wasn't always this way.
He truly cares for Karan.
He's just going about things the wrong way.
I was born and raised here too.
I understand how he feels.
When did you learn about the missing people?
A month ago.
I told him countless times to stop,
but he wouldn't listen.
We had to be careful,
lest he try to silence us.
But I'm Karan's best blacksmith,
if I do say so myself.
In other words, the city needs you to prosper.
Yeah, but the governor didn't
just refuse to listen to me.
He demanded my cooperation.
He threatened to kill Goh and
Miranda if I didn't do as he said.
So I've been keeping my distance,
hoping they wouldn't get dragged into this.
By the way, about the Holy Sword Rand...
Oh, yeah. Let Theron keep the sword.
He's the one who found it.
It belongs to Karan!
It's a priceless national treasure!
Yeah, that may be.
Firstly, Gazus, we just saved your life.
Isn't that right?
A-And I'm grateful, but...
In addition, Theron and my friends here
protected Goh when your home was attacked.
Then, during the slaughter at the embassy,
I drove off the demon and protected
Miranda, who was also there.
In other words, we've saved
three lives, yours included.
On top of that, you've had trouble
sourcing mithril, no?
In that case...
I-Is this mithril?
Yeah. We excavated a ton
from some Xarles ruins.
One of our goals in coming to Karan was
to find a blacksmith who could use it.
You probably are the best
blacksmith on the continent.
You may eventually forge a blade
greater than the holy sword.
G-Greater than the holy sword?
We'll provide the mithril you need to do it.
Use as much as you'd like.
A-As much mithril as I'd like?
Picture it.
Imagine yourself using all the high-quality
mithril you want to forge a sword.
Now then, considering our fantastic offer,
surely there won't be a problem
with one holy sword going missing.
B-But...
The holy sword was never
in Karan. Isn't that right?
I-If you say so.
I'm glad Gazus is the kind of guy who
lets his partner call the shots.
Next up, there's something
I'd like you to make.
You want me to make this?
Yeah. Think you can do it?
Now that mithril's not an issue, sure.
But it'll take me three days.
Do it in two.
Two days?!
Don't be ridiculous!
It's ridiculous but not impossible, right?
I have a duel three days from now.
I need it before then. Please.
Damn it! The man who saved my life
just had to be this pain in the ass.
Damn it all!
I gotta get my ass to the forge and hole up.
Miranda, look after Goh for a while.
We're all set there now.
That just leaves...
Are you two okay?
Yeah. We weren't seriously injured.
I still think that female
demon was holding back.
I couldn't land a single attack.
I had no idea demons were so strong.
The elders of my hometown
described them as fearsome.
It seems they did not exaggerate.
Their power is on another level.
You don't have to force yourselves to fight—
But it's okay!
We'll win next time!
Right?
Yes. They think we are beneath them.
We can exploit that.
I was planning to tag in
Theron next time, but...
I didn't think they'd be so motivated.
So there's nothing for me to do?
No. If it comes to it,
cut the demons down from behind.
The dirty work's on me, then.
You said this would be a fair duel.
All part of my plan.
You're one nasty dude.
Was putting off the fight even necessary?
Yeah. I can't have them getting
cornered and desperate.
Oh, right. The magic circle.
But still...
You're just itching to use the holy sword.
Well, yeah, of course.
Besides, the male demon didn't seem
too concerned with the holy sword,
so we needed to get our hands on that.
You were after his horn from the start?
Either way, those demons were pretty strong.
We won't necessarily win in a fair fight.
I know.
That's why I asked for three days.
It's definitely on the brink of imploding.
We need to do something about it.
Releasing magic power is simple.
Once you learn how, even you could do it.
The magic power in this catalyst...
Can't I transfer it to the
Divine Dragon's Heart?
I see. This thing could easily store enough
magic power to destroy a city.
It'll take days to complete the transfer.
Out of curiosity,
was it even possible to use earth-shifting
magic to force more mithril to the surface?
No. All the veins in this
area have been depleted.
I thought so.
Even if they'd been able to gather more,
it would have altered the landscape.
This city would have still been destroyed.
So everything the governor did was for naught.
The duel is tomorrow!
How can he be so relaxed?!
I prefer it that way.
We can't afford to lose.
To prevent the Great Invasion,
what we need most is intel on demons.
In particular, about the next demon king.
They're not here yet.
It was a mistake not to specify a time.
You've always been like this.
You forget the important details.
I doubt they'll show up soon,
so why don't we have some tea?
More importantly, did you come up with a plan?
You bet!
I'm not so arrogant as to think
our victory is certain,
but we do have a shot.
So you didn't run away, hmm?
We've been waiting for you!
Kyle, you've got crumbs on you.
What?
What a slob.
Sheesh.
Get this cleaned up.
Theron, don't just sit there.
How did you make such a mess?
Sorry.
Honestly, I'm amazed you'd have tea
before a duel with demons.
You didn't have to!
I'm not the one fighting.
You lot requested this duel.
Do you mean to mock us?
Let them be.
They're trying to lower our
guard and stoke our rage.
Sorry about the wait.
Now, let's settle this.
However...
First, why don't we go elsewhere?
You and I will fight one-on-one, but this
chamber's too cramped for two fights at once.
As you wish.
You'll just be choosing where you die.
Are you sure?
Won't this give them an advantage?
I don't care if they have
tricks up their sleeve.
I shall utterly destroy him.
Follow me.
The rest is up to you guys.
Sure!
You're staying here?
I'm to inform him immediately
if anything happens here.
Normally I should stay with my sword,
but as long as I still supply it
with magic power, it's fine.
Now then, are you prepared?
I'm just here as a witness.
If you beat those two,
I'll give you the holy sword.
I see.
Honestly, I don't want to do this,
but it's for the sword.
I learned from our previous fight
that you're reasonably strong.
This time, I will fight at full strength.
If you don't want to die,
you should surrender soon.
This is bad.
It's a bit unexpected,
but if they can survive the first attack,
it should be a decent fight.
She's so fast!
Way faster than before!
Salamander!
Yikes.
Hot stuff!
You're in the way!
Gnome!
Two at once?
Got—
She just grazed me,
but I can barely stay conscious!
No you don't!
As I thought,
the difference in power is clear.
Shouldn't you help them?
You're not wrong, but if I'm not careful,
they'll kill me later for interfering.
Besides, the situation isn't that bad.
She's strong.
Yeah, but...
I wouldn't say she's unbeatable.
You're quite tough, but it's time to end this!
Gnome!
Futile!
Liese!
On it!
I'll tear through you and your spirit!
What...?
One more where that came from!
The gnome wasn't a shield.
It was there to block my view.
How dare you?!
Huh.
All right!
This place will do.
Now, let us begin.
Next Time
Secret Red-Hot Strategy
Next time: "Secret Red-Hot Strategy."